Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Telegraph Workers PE.025
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Telegraph Workers
1916-1990
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
PE.025
2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Telegraph Workers is an artificial collection, collected and assembled by the Tamiment Library over the course of several decades. It consists of contracts, agreements and constitutions from the United Telegraph Workers as well as its predecessor, the Commercial Telegraphers' Union of America. There are also files from the various divisions of the Union, representing workers from Canada and the United States who worked for the Canadian Pacific System, the United Press System, and the Western Union, among others.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Custodial History
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with labor unions and other organizations, exchanges with other libraries, and through ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series: Series I: Commercial Telegraphers' Union of America, 1916-1966; Series II: United Telegraph Workers, 1968-1990; Series III: Divisions, 1916-1986. Folders are arranged alphabetically within series.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Guide to the United Telegraph Workers Records (WAG 144)
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Telegraph Workers largely consists of agreements, contracts and constitutions, as well as a few pamphlets and publications. Material comes from the predecessor Commercial Telegraphers' Union of America as well as from various divisions from around the United States and Canada, including the divisions that represented the Canadian Pacific System, the Associated Press System, the United Press System, and Western Union.
Historical/Biographical Note
The United Telegraph Workers was known until 1968 as the Commercial Telegraphers' Union of America. Founded in convention in New York City in 1903, the Commercial Telegraphers' Union of America emerged from a series of struggles between smaller unions of private and postal telegraph workers. At the time, over one hundred delegates represented seventy-five locals from across the country. During World War II and throughout much of its history, the union had been pitted against a single dominant employer, Western Union. Due to technological change in the industry and charged anti-union efforts, the Commercial Telegrapher's Union of America declined in numbers after World War II. In 1986, the 5,800 member United Telegraph Workers merged with the Communications Workers of America.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library. There is no accession record associated with this collection.
Constitutions.; Pamphlets.; Agreements.; Contracts; Telegraphers.; Telegraphers |x Labor unions.; Labor unions; Telegraph |x Employees.; Labor unions -- United States.; United Telegraph Workers; Commercial Telegraphers' Union of America
- Series I: Commercial Telegraphers' Union of America, 1920-1966
  - Agreements and Contracts, 1920-1966 (Box 1)
  - By-Laws, 1922-1955 (Box 2)
  - Constitutions, 1920-1928 (Box 2)
  - Constitutions, 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - Constitutions, 1951-1963 (Box 2)
  - Conventions, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets and Publications, 1929-1947, undated (Box 2)
  - Radio Officers' Union, 1941-1961 (Box 2)
  - Strikes, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Western Union Organizing Committee, circa 1947 (Box 2)
- Series II: United Telegraph Workers, 1968-1990
  - Agreements and Contracts, 1968-1990 (Box 1)
  - Constitutions, 1971-1979 (Box 2)
  - Constitutions, 1983-1986 (Box 2)
  - Strikes, 1971 (Box 2)
- Series III: Divisions, 1916-1986
  - Division 1 (Canadian Pacific System): By-Laws, 1925-1967 (Box 2)
  - Division 1 (Canadian Pacific System): Rules and Wages, 1916-1942 (Box 2)
  - Division 14 (Associated Press System), 1949-1956 (Box 2)
  - Division 14 (Associated Press System): By-Laws, 1939-1965 (Box 2)
  - Division 14 (Associated Press System): By-Laws, 1972-1982 (Box 2)
  - Division 47 (United Press System): By-Laws, 1929-1962 (Box 2)
  - Division 47 (United Press System): Contracts and Seniority Record, 1946-1953 (Box 2)
  - Division 47 (United Press System): Pension Plan, 1960, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Division 61 (International News Service), 1918, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Southwestern Division: Constitutions, 1959-1967 (Box 2)
  - Western Union Division: By-Laws, 1943-1957 (Box 2)
  - Western Union Division: By-Laws, 1959-1971 (Box 2)
  - Western Union Division: By-Laws (Various Locals), 1966-1986 (Box 2)